ICICI Prudential Life Insurance has
reported a strong fourth quarter with a
net profit jumping 58% year-on-year to
rupees 609 crore while premium income
rose 17%. Growth in value of new
business and margins also remained
robust. For a deeper dive into the
numbers, let's now go across to my
colleague Summit for more details.
Summit, break it down for our viewers.
Well, pretty much in line set of numbers
that ICICI Prudential Life has reported
in the fourth quarter compared to what
the street was anticipating. Now, if you
look at the net profit number, they look
58% higher, but that is also because of
a lower base in the previous year. VNB
again, that is the value of new business
grew 21% on the back of lower base to
close to 965 crore rupees as against 795
crore that the company had reported in
the previous quarter. AP growth around 9
grew around 9% while the net premium
earned was also up 17%. Now, we do not
have the VNB margins for the fourth
quarter, but for the full financial
year, that is for FY26, the company has
reported a VNB margin of 24.7%
as against 22.8% that the company had
reported in FY25. And the embedded
value, which is also quite important for
the valuation perspective, has jumped up
by nearly 10 and a half percent to close
to 52,989
crore rupees. Now, persistency ratio,
which measure the number of
the persistency ratio or the retention
ratio for 13 month that stood at close
to 82.1%
while for the 61st month stood at close
to 61.2%.
Now, the company is yet to hold the
conference call, but the key thing to
watch out for from the conference call
would be their FY27 guidance that the
company has given because FY26, I
believe the company has missed their
growth guidance, but the FY27 guidance
would be important to track from the
conference call that ICICI Prudential
Life will be holding.
Thank you so much
Summit for that perspective. And
yesterday, ICICI Prudential AMC also
announced their quarter four numbers.
The company reported a mixed quarter as
profits declined by nearly 70%
sequentially. The management attributed
the slump in bottom line to
market-to-market losses. During the con
call, my colleague Sharad Dubey got a
chance to speak to the management of
ICICI Prudential AMC. Listen in to what
they had to speak about the demand
trends.
In terms of the operational front,
how do you see this panning out for this
current quarter as well? I will be
seeing this
because on March, we see some
adjustments also take place in the
industry as well. So, will we see some
impact of the war in the month of April?
What are the initial trends suggesting?
I always like an environment where the
customer is slightly asking more
questions before investing.
It is always a very healthy kind of
sales when customer is a bit skeptical.
Before investing, if a customer is
asking more questions and is being
skeptical, it's a good
this one because more responsible sales
are happening. It is not happening based
on euphoria. It is happening in a
uncertain environment. So,
flows, as you have seen in the month of
March, air four flows have flows have
held on to
Initially, the customer has not It is
now 18 months
since September 24, it is 18 months
where the equity markets are subdued,
but the flows are on.